Guide to the Exiles Film Project records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Exiles Film Project records
1984-1989
MS 1734
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
102.75
The records consist of interviews, interview transcripts, editing and production records, and film footage created during the making of the film, The Exiles. The film, written by Richard Kaplan and Lou Potter, and produced by Richard Kaplan Productions, was released in 1989. Its focus is the European artists, scholars, and intellectuals, mostly Jewish, who escaped totalitarianism and emigrated to America before and during World War II. The film traces their lives in Europe, their escapes, and their impact on American cultural and intellectual life.
Richard Kaplan Productions
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Richard Kaplan, 1996.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research. Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Biographical / Historical
The Exiles, a film written by Richard Kaplan and Lou Potter, and produced by Richard Kaplan Productions, was released in 1989 and shown on WNET (public television) in New York City. Its focus is the European artists, scholars, and intellectuals, mostly Jewish, who escaped totalitarianism and emigrated to America before and during World War II. The film traces their lives in Europe, their escapes, and their impact on American cultural and intellectual life.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of interviews, interview transcripts, editing and production records, and film footage created during the making of the film, The Exiles. Interview subjects come from a variety of fields including: anthropology (Claude Levi-Strauss); art (Josef Albers, Robert Motherwell); chemistry (Herman Mark); criticism (Frederic Morton); economics (Albert Hirschman, Franco Modigliani); engineering (Mario Salvadori); film and theatre (Dolly Haas, Henry Koster, Erwin Piscator, Rod Steiger, Billy Wilder); history (Felix Gilbert, Hanna Grey, Robert Heilbroner, H. Stuart Hughes, Golo Mann, Peter Selz); law (Henry Ehrmann); music (Kurt Adler, Erich Leinsdorf); philosophy (Hans Jonas); photography (Alfred Eisenstaedt); physics (Hans Bethe, Edward Teller); poetry (Hans Sahl); political science (Erich Hula, Konrad Kellen); psychiatry (Bruno Bettelheim); psychology (Ernest Dichter, Marie Jahoda); publishing (Helen Wolff); sociology (Adolph Lowe, Leo Löwenthal, Hans Speier); and theology (Wolfgang Roth).
Original (creator assigned) media numbers have been retained: Audio cassettes are numbered 1-118; Betacams are denoted B (or R) 5000-5053; U-matic tapes are denoted U1-U7; VHS tapes are numbered 1-30, or by an identifier from a different format to indicate a VHS copy. Some media have multiple identifiers, to indicate the same interview subject across different formats. Production records contain further documentation on identifiers and interview copies across multiple formats.
Arrangement
The material is arranged into four groupings: interview transcripts, interviews, kine sync film reels, and production material.
Documentary films; Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945); Intellectuals; National socialism and intellectuals; Political refugees; World War, 1939-1945 -- Personal narratives, Jewish; World War, 1939-1945; Kaplan, Richard; Potter, Lou; New School for Social Research (New York, N.Y.: 1919-1997); Richard Kaplan Productions
- Transcripts of audio interviews, Series I
  - Volume I
    - Adler, Kurt (Box 1)
    - Albers, Anni (Box 1)
    - Allner, Walter (Box 1)
    - Benedite, Daniel (Box 1)
    - Bethe, Hans (Box 1)
    - Bettelheim, Bruno (Box 1)
    - Bingham, Hiram (Box 1)
    - Deyrup, Felicia (Box 1)
    - Dichter, Ernst (Box 1)
    - Ehrmann, Henry and Claire (Box 1)
  - Volume II
    - Eisenstaedt, Alfred (Box 1)
    - Gilbert, Felix (Box 1)
    - Gold, Mary Jayne (Box 1)
    - Gray, Hanna (Box 1)
    - Haas, Dolly (Box 1)
    - Hirschman, Albert (Box 1)
    - Hughes, H. Stuart (Box 1)
    - Hula, Erich (Box 1)
  - Volume III
    - Johnson, Peter (Box 1)
    - Jonas, Hans (Box 1)
    - Kellen, Konrad (Box 1)
    - Koster, Henry (Box 1)
    - Landshoff, Fritz (Box 1)
    - Leinsdorf, Erich (Box 1)
    - Lerner, Ralph (Box 1)
    - Lowe, Adolph (Box 1)
    - Lowenthal, Leo (Box 1)
  - Volume IV
    - Mann, Golo (Box 2)
    - Motherwell, Robert (Box 2)
    - Nona, Nuria (Box 2)
    - Oram, Harold (Box 2)
    - Piscator, Maria (Box 2)
    - Redfield, James (Box 2)
    - Roth, Wolfgang (Box 2)
    - Salvadori, Mario (Box 2)
    - Selz, Peter (Box 2)
  - Volume V
    - Speier, Hans (Box 2)
    - Teller, Edward (Box 2)
    - Tillich, Hanna (Box 2)
    - Waldo, Hilde (Box 2)
    - Weiner, Lynne (Box 2)
    - Wilder, Billy (Box 2)
    - Wolff, Helen (Box 2)
    - Zimmer, Christiane (Box 2)
- Interviews, Series II
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - Adler, Kurt
    - Adler, Kurt, 1985 May 17; 12; 1.0 (Box 3)
    - Adler, Kurt, 1985 May 17; 13; 1.0 (Box 4)
  - Albers, Josef/Allner
    - Albers, Josef/Allner, Circa 1980s; B5039, 40; 1.0 (Box 5)
    - Albers, Josef/Allner, 1988 March 25; B5039; 1.0 (Box 6)
    - Albers, Josef/Allner, 1988 March 25; B5040; 1.0 (Box 7)
    - Albers, Josef/Allner and Felicia Deyrup, 1988 March 25; B5039, B5040, B5041; 1.0 (Box 8)
  - Assignment Rescue, parts one and two, a radio broadcast, Circa 1980s; 1.0 (Box 9)
  - Bennidte, Danny
    - Bennidte, Danny- Paris, 1985 June 25; 51; 1.0 (Box 10)
    - Bennidte, Danny, 1985 June 25; 52; 1.0 (Box 11)
  - Bethe, Hans
    - Bethe, Hans, 1985 June 6; 22; 1.0 (Box 12)
    - Bethe, Hans, 1985 June 25; 23; 1.0 (Box 13)
    - Bethe, Hans, 1985 June 25; 24A; 1.0 (Box 14)
    - Bethe, Hans, 1988 August 24; 118; 1.0 (Box 15)
    - Bethe 1 of 3, Modigliani room tone only, Circa 1980s; B5051; 1.0 (Box 16)
    - Bethe 2 of 3, 1988 August; B5052; 1.0 (Box 17)
    - Bethe 3 of 3, 1988 August; B5053; 1.0 (Box 18)
  - Bettelheim, Bruno
    - Bettelheim, Bruno, 1985 May 21; 17A; 1.0 (Box 19)
    - Bettelheim, Bruno, 1985 May 21; 18A; 1.0 (Box 20)
    - Bettelheim, Bruno, 1988 January 27; 82, 5007, 5008; 1.0 (Box 21)
    - Bettelheim, Bruno, 1988 January 27; Reel 5006; 1.0 (Box 22)
    - Bettelheim, Bruno, 1988 January 27; Reel 5007; 1.0 (Box 23)
    - Bettelheim, Bruno, 1988 January 27; Reel 5008; 1.0 (Box 24)
  - Bingham, Hiram, 1987 August 4; 61; 1.0 (Box 25)
  - Deyrup, Felicia
    - Deyrup, Felicia, 1988 May 16; 104; 1.0 (Box 26)
    - Deyrup, Felicia, Circa 1980s; 100, B5041, 42; 1.0 (Box 27)
    - Deyrup, Felicia, 1988 March 25; B5041; 1.0 (Box 28)
    - Deyrup, Felicia, 1988 March 25; B5042; 1.0 (Box 29)
    - Deyrup, Felicia, at Rockefeller Archive 1 of 2, 1988 May 16; B5045; 1.0 (Box 30)
    - Deyrup, Felicia, at Rockefeller Archive 2 of 2, 1988 May 16; B5046; 1.0 (Box 31)
    - Deyrup, Felicia, 1988 March 25; 47, B5042; 1.0 (Box 32)
    - Deyrup, Felicia, Circa 1980s; 49, B5045, 5046; 1.0 (Box 33)
  - Dichter, Ernest
    - Dichter, Ernest, 1985 May 6; 7; 1.0 (Box 34)
    - Dichter, Ernest, 1985 May 6; 8; 1.0 (Box 35)
    - Dichter, Ernest, Circa 1980s; 97A, B5035, 36; 1.0 (Box 36)
    - Dichter, Ernest, Circa 1980s; 97AA; 1.0 (Box 37)
    - Dichter, Ernest, and Mrs. Lynn Weiner, Circa 1980s; 98, B5037, 5038; 1.0 (Box 38)
    - Dichter, Ernest, 1988 March 24; B5035; 1.0 (Box 39)
    - Dichter, Ernest, 1988 March 24; B5036; 1.0 (Box 40)
    - Dichter, Ernest, 1988 March 24; B5037; 1.0 (Box 41)
    - Dichter, Ernest, and Erich Leinsdorf, 1988 March 24; 44, B5033, B5034, B5035; 1.0 (Box 42)
    - Dichter, Ernest and Weiner, 1988 March 24; 45, B5036, B5037, B5038; 1.0 (Box 43)
  - Ehrendoktor
    - Ehrendoktor; Berlin, Circa 1980s; U1; 1.0 (Box 44)
    - Ehrendoktor, Circa 1980s; 1; 1.0 (Box 45)
    - Ehrendoktor, Circa 1980s; 2; 1.0 (Box 46)
    - Ehrendoktor, Circa 1980s; 3; 1.0 (Box 47)
    - Ehrendoktor part 1, Berlin, Circa 1980s; 23 (U1); 1.0 (Box 48)
    - Ehrendoktor part 2, Adolph Lowe part 1, Circa 1980s; 24; 1.0 (Box 49)
  - Ehrmann
    - Ehrmann, Henry- Hanover, New Hampshire, 1987 September 20; 87-R1; 1.0 (Box 50)
    - Ehrmann, Claire (Side A); Loeb, Anna (Side B), 1987 September 20; 87-R2; 1.0 (Box 51)
    - Ehrmann audio interviews, Ehrmann ITW 1, Cerbere 2, 1988 June 1; 1.0 (Box 52)
    - Ehrmann audio interviews, Ehrmann ITW 2, Cerbere 3, 1988 June 1; 1.0 (Box 53)
  - Eisenstaedt, Alfred
    - Eisenstaedt, Alfred, 1985 December 3; 53A, 53B; 1.0 (Box 54)
    - Eisenstaedt, Alfred, 1985 December 3; 66A from videotape B14, 66B from videotape B15; 1.0 (Box 55)
    - Eisenstaedt, Alfred, 1985 December 3; 12; 1.0 (Box 56)
    - Eisenstaedt, Alfred, 1985 December 3; 13; 1.0 (Box 57)
    - Eisenstaedt, Alfred, 1985 December 3; 14; 1.0 (Box 58)
    - Eisenstaedt, Alfred, 1985 December 3; 15; 1.0 (Box 59)
    - Eisenstaedt, Alfred- Roll 12, 13, 1985 December 3; 12; 1.0 (Box 60)
    - Eisenstaedt, Alfred- Roll 13, 14, 1985 December 3; 13; 1.0 (Box 61)
    - Eisenstaedt, Alfred- Roll 14, 1985 December 3; 14; 1.0 (Box 62)
  - Ernst, Max, Circa 1980s; 1.0 (Box 63)
  - The Exiles
    - The Exiles voice over, Bill St. James, 1989 June 21; 1.0 (Box 64)
    - "The Exiles Project" The Exile Master voice over reel, 1989 February 24; 1.0 (Box 65)
    - The Exiles, Circa 1980s; B5001 through B5003; 1.0 (Box 66)
    - The Exiles, 1988 January 26; Reel 5003; 1.0 (Box 67)
    - The Exiles, Circa 1980s; B5004 through B5006; 1.0 (Box 68)
    - The Exiles, Circa 1980s; B5007 through B5009; 1.0 (Box 69)
    - The Exiles, Circa 1980s; B5010 through B5012; 1.0 (Box 70)
    - The Exiles, 1988 January 27; Reel 5011; 1.0 (Box 71)
    - The Exiles, Circa 1980s; B5012 through B5015; 1.0 (Box 72)
    - The Exiles, 1988 January 28; Reel 5014; 1.0 (Box 73)
    - The Exiles, 1988 January 28; Reel 5015; 1.0 (Box 74)
    - The Exiles, Circa 1980s; B5016 through B5018; 1.0 (Box 75)
    - The Exiles, Circa 1980s; B5019 through B5021; 1.0 (Box 76)
    - The Exiles, Circa 1980s; B5048 through B5050; 1.0 (Box 77)
    - The Exiles, Circa 1980s; B5051 through B5053; 1.0 (Box 78)
  - Gilbert, Felix, 1985 May 18; 1; 1.0 (Box 79)
  - Gold, Mary Jayne
    - Gold, Mary Jayne, Circa 1980s; 3; 1.0 (Box 80)
    - Gold, Mary Jayne, Circa 1980s; 4; 1.0 (Box 81)
    - Gold, Mary Jayne audio interviews, Marseille ITW MJ Gold 1, 1988 June 2; 1.0 (Box 82)
    - Gold, Mary Jayne audio interviews, Marseille ITW MJ Gold 2, 1988 June 2; 1.0 (Box 83)
  - Gray, Hanna
    - Gray, Hanna, 1988 January 29; 88, B5019-5020; 1.0 (Box 84)
    - Gray, Hanna, 1988 January 29; 89A, B5021; 1.0 (Box 85)
    - Gray, Hanna, and Ralph Lerner room tone, 1988 January 29; B5019; 1.0 (Box 86)
    - Gray, Hanna, 1988 January 29; B5020; 1.0 (Box 87)
    - Gray, Hanna, 1988 January 29; B5021; 1.0 (Box 88)
  - Haas, Dolly
    - Haas, Dolly, 1988 March 23; 95, B5031-32; 1.0 (Box 89)
    - Haas, Dolly, 1988 March 23; B5031; 1.0 (Box 90)
    - Haas, Dolly, 1988 March 23; B5032; 1.0 (Box 91)
  - Heilbroner, Robert, 1985 December 16; 54; 1.0 (Box 92)
  - Hirschman, Albert
    - Hirschman, Albert, 1985 May 1; 5; 1.0 (Box 93)
    - Hirschman, Albert, 1985 May 1; 6; 1.0 (Box 94)
    - Hirschman, Albert, 1985 October 22; 59; 1.0 (Box 95)
    - Hirschman, Albert, 1985 October 25; 60; 1.0 (Box 96)
    - Hirschman, Albert, and Wolfgang Roth, 1985 October 25; 63; 1.0 (Box 97)
    - Hirschman, Albert, Circa 1980s; 64-65, VHS 4-5; 1.0 (Box 98)
    - Hirschman, Albert, 1985 October 22; 1; 1.0 (Box 99)
    - Hirschman, Albert, 1985 October 22; 3; 1.0 (Box 100)
    - Hirschman, Albert, 1985 October 22; 4; 1.0 (Box 101)
    - Hirschman, Albert, 1985 October 22; 5; 1.0 (Box 102)
    - Hirschman, Albert, 1985 October 22; 9; 1.0 (Box 103)
    - Hirschman, Albert, 1985 October 22; 10; 1.0 (Box 104)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Original multi-channel audio recording. The interviewee alone on the left channel and the interviewer and interviewee are both present on the right channel. At 11:23 into the recording, the microphone on the left channel is moved, and it produces a very loud static, noise and hiss, which makes the entire recording unlistenable until 15:29. In the digital preservation master recording, the left audio channel has been removed during this period in order to make it listenable.
    - Hirschman, Albert, 1985 October 22; 11; 1.0 (Box 105)
    - Hirschman, Albert, 1985 October 22; 1; 1.0 (Box 106)
    - Hirschman, Albert, 1985 October 22; 1, 2nd copy; 1.0 (Box 107)
    - Hirschman, Albert, 1985 October 22; 3; 1.0 (Box 108)
    - Hirschman, Albert, 1985 October 22; 3, 2nd copy; 1.0 (Box 109)
    - Hirschman, Albert, 1985 October 22; 4; 1.0 (Box 110)
    - Hirschman, Albert, 1985 October 22; 4, 2nd copy; 1.0 (Box 111)
    - Hirschman, Albert, 1985 October 22; 5; 1.0 (Box 112)
    - Hirschman, Albert, 1985 October 25; 9; 1.0 (Box 113)
    - Hirschman, Albert, 1985 October 25; 10; 1.0 (Box 114)
    - Hirschman, Albert, 1985 October 25; 11; 1.0 (Box 115)
  - Hughes, H. Stuart
    - Hughes, H. Stuart, 1985 May 30; 20; 1.0 (Box 116)
    - Hughes, H. Stuart, 1988 January 27; 85, B5013, B5014; 1.0 (Box 117)
    - Hughes, H. Stuart (Side A), Redfield, James (Side B), 1988 January 28; 86, B5015, B5016; 1.0 (Box 118)
    - Hughes, H. Stuart, 1988 October 22; B5013; 1.0 (Box 119)
  - Hula, Erich, 1985 June 10; 25; 1.0 (Box 120)
  - Jahoda, Marie
    - Jahoda, Marie, Circa 1980s; 36; 1.0 (Box 121)
    - Jahoda, Marie, Circa 1980s; 37; 1.0 (Box 122)
  - Johnson, Peter
    - Johnson, Peter, 1988 May 16; 103; 1.0 (Box 123)
    - Johnson, Peter, 1988 May 16; B5043; 1.0 (Box 124)
    - Johnson, Peter, 1988 May 16; B5044; 1.0 (Box 125)
    - Johnson, Peter, Circa 1980s; B5043, B5044; 1.0 (Box 126)
  - Jonas, Hans
    - Jonas, Hans, 1985 June 10; 28; 1.0 (Box 127)
    - Jonas, Hans, 1985 June 10; 29; 1.0 (Box 128)
    - Jonas, Hans, Circa 1980s; 57A, 20; 57B, 21, 22; 1.0 (Box 129)
    - Jonas, Hans, 1986 January 21; 17; 1.0 (Box 130)
    - Jonas, Hans, 1986 January 21; 18; 1.0 (Box 131)
    - Jonas, Hans, 1986 January 21; 19; 1.0 (Box 132)
    - Jonas, Hans, 1986 January 21; 20; 1.0 (Box 133)
    - Jonas, Hans, 1986 January 21; 21; 1.0 (Box 134)
    - Jonas, Hans, 1986 January 21; 22; 1.0 (Box 135)
    - Jonas, Hans- Dub, Circa 1980s; 17; 1.0 (Box 136)
    - Jonas, Hans, Circa 1980s; 18; 1.0 (Box 137)
    - Jonas, Hans, Circa 1980s; 19; 1.0 (Box 138)
    - Jonas, Hans, Circa 1980s; 20; 1.0 (Box 139)
    - Jonas, Hans, Circa 1980s; 21; 1.0 (Box 140)
    - Jonas, Hans, Circa 1980s; 22; 1.0 (Box 141)
  - Kellen, Konrad
    - Kellen, Konrad, 1988 January 27; 84, 5011, 5012; 1.0 (Box 142)
    - Kellen, Konrad, 1988 January 27; R2012; 1.0 (Box 143)
  - Koster, Henry, Circa 1980s; 19; 1.0 (Box 144)
  - Landshoff, Fritz
    - Landshoff, Fritz, 1985 June 19; 48; 1.0 (Box 145)
    - Landshoff, Fritz, 1985 June 19; 49; 1.0 (Box 146)
  - Leinsdorf, Erich
    - Leinsdorf, Erich, 1985 June 7; 25; 1.0 (Box 147)
    - Leinsdorf, Erich, Circa 1980s; 96; 1.0 (Box 148)
    - Leinsdorf, Erich, 1988 March 24; B5033; 1.0 (Box 149)
    - Leinsdorf, Erich, 1988 March 24; B5034; 1.0 (Box 150)
  - Lerner, Ralph
    - Lerner, Ralph, 1988 January 29; 87, 5017, 5018; 1.0 (Box 151)
    - Lerner, Ralph, 1988 January 29; B5017; 1.0 (Box 152)
    - Lerner, Ralph, 1988 January 29; B5018; 1.0 (Box 153)
  - Levi-Strauss, Claude, 1985 June 24; 50; 1.0 (Box 154)
  - Lowe, Adolph
    - Lowe, Adolph, 1985 June 29; 37; 1.0 (Box 155)
    - Lowe, Adolph, 1985 June 29; 38; 1.0 (Box 156)
    - Lowe, Adolph, 1985 June 29; 39; 1.0 (Box 157)
    - Lowe, Adolph, 1985 June 29; 40; 1.0 (Box 158)
    - Lowe, Adolph, 1985 June 29; 41; 1.0 (Box 159)
    - Lowe, Adolph, Circa 1980s; U2; 1.0 (Box 160)
    - Lowe, Adolph- Sound Channel I, MKII team Berlin, 1985 June 29; 4; 1.0 (Box 161)
    - Lowe, Adolph- Sound Channel I, MKII team Berlin, 1985 June 29; 5; 1.0 (Box 162)
    - Lowe, Adolph- Sound Channel I, MKII team Berlin, 1985 June 29; 6; 1.0 (Box 163)
    - Lowe, Adolph- Sound Channel I, MKII team Berlin, 1985 June 29; 7; 1.0 (Box 164)
    - Lowe, Adolph- Sound Channel I, MKII team Berlin, 1985 June 29; 8; 1.0 (Box 165)
    - Lowe, Adolph part 2, Circa 1980s; 25 (U2); 1.0 (Box 166)
    - Lowe, Adolph part 3, Circa 1980s; 26 (U2, U3); 1.0 (Box 167)
    - Lowe, Adolph part 4, Leo Lowenthal part 1, Circa 1980s; 27 (U3, U4); 1.0 (Box 168)
    - Lowe, Adolph, and Leo Lowenthal, Circa 1980s; U3; 1.0 (Box 169)
  - Lowenthal, Leo
    - Lowenthal, Leo, 1985 July 16; 42; 1.0 (Box 170)
    - Lowenthal, Leo, 1985 July 16; 43; 1.0 (Box 171)
    - Lowenthal, Leo, 1985 July 16; 44; 1.0 (Box 172)
    - Lowenthal, Leo- audio channel I, MKII team, 1985 July 16; 9; 1.0 (Box 173)
    - Lowenthal, Leo- audio channel I, MKII team, 1985 July 16; 10; 1.0 (Box 174)
    - Lowenthal, Leo- audio channel I, MKII team, 1985 July 16; 11; 1.0 (Box 175)
    - Lowenthal, Leo, Circa 1980s; 28 (U4); 1.0 (Box 176)
    - Lowenthal, Leo and Golo Mann, Circa 1980s; U4; 1.0 (Box 177)
  - Mann, Golo
    - Mann, Golo, 1985 July 23; 45; 1.0 (Box 178)
    - Mann, Golo, 1985 July 23; 46; 1.0 (Box 179)
    - Mann, Golo, 1985 July 23; 47; 1.0 (Box 180)
    - Mann, Golo, Circa 1980s; U5; 1.0 (Box 181)
    - Mann, Golo- Zurich, Audio Channel I, MKII team, 1985 July 23; 12; 1.0 (Box 182)
    - Mann, Golo- Zurich, Audio Channel I, MKII team, 1985 July 23; 13; 1.0 (Box 183)
    - Mann, Golo- Zurich, Audio Channel I, MKII team, 1985 July 23; 14; 1.0 (Box 184)
    - Mann, Golo- Zurich, Audio Channel I, MKII team, 1985 July 23; 15; 1.0 (Box 185)
    - Mann, Golo part 1, Circa 1980s; 29, (U4, U5); 1.0 (Box 186)
    - Mann, Golo part 2, Circa 1980s; 30, (U5); 1.0 (Box 187)
  - Mark, Herman, 1986 January 22; 58; 1.0 (Box 188)
  - Modigliani, Franco
    - Modigliani, Franco, 1988 August 23; B5050, 5051 (room tone); 1.0 (Box 189)
    - Modigliani, Franco interview, Circa 1980s; B5050; 1.0 (Box 190)
  - Morton, Fredric, Circa 1980s; 55; 1.0 (Box 191)
  - Motherwell, Robert
    - Motherwell, Robert, 1988 August 22; 116, transitions to B5049; 1.0 (Box 192)
    - Motherwell, Robert part 1, Circa 1980s; B5048; 1.0 (Box 193)
    - Motherwell, Robert part 2, Circa 1980s; B5049; 1.0 (Box 194)
  - New School
    - New School- First Consultant Meeting, 1984 November 10; 67; 1.0 (Box 195)
    - New School- First Consultant Meeting, 1984 November 10; 68; 1.0 (Box 196)
    - New School- First Consultant Meeting, 1984 November 10; 69; 1.0 (Box 197)
    - New School- First Consultant Meeting, 1984 November 10; 70; 1.0 (Box 198)
  - Nono, Nuria
    - Nono, Nuria, 1988 January 26; 80, B5003, B5004; 1.0 (Box 199)
    - Nono, Nuria (Side A), Bettelheim, Bruno (Side B), 1988 January 26; 81, B5005, B5006; 1.0 (Box 200)
    - Nono, Nuria, 1988 January 26; B5004; 1.0 (Box 201)
    - Nono, Nuria, 1988 January 26; B5005; 1.0 (Box 202)
  - Oram, Harold, 1987 August; 64; 1.0 (Box 203)
  - Piscator
    - Piscator, Erwin, 1987 October 17; 73; 1.0 (Box 204)
    - Piscator, Erwin, 1987 October 17; 74; 1.0 (Box 205)
    - Piscator, Erwin, 1987 October 17; 75; 1.0 (Box 206)
    - Piscator, Maria, 1985 June 9; 26; 1.0 (Box 207)
  - Redfield, James, 1988 January 29; B5016; 1.0 (Box 208)
  - Roth, Wolfgang
    - Roth, Wolfgang, 1985 June 12; 30; 1.0 (Box 209)
    - Roth, Wolfgang, 1985 June 12; 31; 1.0 (Box 210)
    - Roth, Wolfgang, 1985 October 25; 62; 1.0 (Box 211)
    - Roth, Wolfgang, 1985 October 25; 5A; 1.0 (Box 212)
    - Roth, Wolfgang, 1985 October 25; 6; 1.0 (Box 213)
    - Roth, Wolfgang, 1985 October 25; 7; 1.0 (Box 214)
    - Roth, Wolfgang, 1985 October 25; 8; 1.0 (Box 215)
    - Roth, Wolfgang, 1985 October 25; 5A; 1.0 (Box 216)
    - Roth, Wolfgang, 1985 October 25; 6; 1.0 (Box 217)
    - Roth, Wolfgang, 1985 October 25; 7; 1.0 (Box 218)
    - Roth, Wolfgang, 1985 October 25; 8; 1.0 (Box 219)
  - Sahl, Hans
    - Sahl, Hans, 1988 March 23; 102, B5030; 1.0 (Box 220)
    - Sahl, Hans, 1988 March 23; B5030; 1.0 (Box 221)
    - Sahl, Hans and Dolly Haas, 1988 March 23; B5030 (Sahl), B5031, B5032 (Haas); 1.0 (Box 222)
  - Salvadori, Mario
    - Salvadori, Mario, 1985 April 29; 1; 1.0 (Box 223)
    - Salvadori, Mario, 1985 April 29; 2; 1.0 (Box 224)
    - Salvadori, Mario, 1988 March 23; 101, B5028; 1.0 (Box 225)
    - Salvadori, Mario, Circa 1980s; B5028; 1.0 (Box 226)
    - Salvadori, Mario, Circa 1980s; B5029; 1.0 (Box 227)
    - Salvadori, Mario, Circa 1980s; B5029, B5029; 1.0 (Box 228)
  - Selz, Peter
    - Selz, Peter- Berkeley, California, 1985 May 19; 14; 1.0 (Box 229)
    - Selz, Peter, 1988 March 4; 92; 1.0 (Box 230)
    - Selz, Peter, 1988 March 4; 93; 1.0 (Box 231)
    - Selz, Peter, 1988 March 4; B5026; 1.0 (Box 232)
    - Selz, Peter, 1988 March 4; B5027; 1.0 (Box 233)
    - Selz, Peter, 1988 March 4; 5026, 5027; 1.0 (Box 234)
  - Speier, Hans
    - Speier, Hans rolls 1 and 2, 1985 October 15; 77; 1.0 (Box 235)
    - Speier, Hans rolls 1 and 2, 1985 October 15; 1.0 (Box 236)
    - Speier, Hans (Europe), 1988 May; 105; 1.0 (Box 237)
    - Speier, Hans interview, shooting in Hamburg 1, 1988 May 26; 1.0 (Box 238)
    - Speier, Hans interview, shooting in Hamburg 2, 1988 May 26; 1.0 (Box 239)
    - Speier, Hans "University in Exile" (New School) 1, Circa 1980s; U6; 1.0 (Box 240)
    - Speier, Hans "University in Exile" (New School) 2, Circa 1980s; U7; 1.0 (Box 241)
    - Speier, Hans, Circa 1980s; U6; 1.0 (Box 242)
    - Speier, Hans, Circa 1980s; U7; 1.0 (Box 243)
  - Steiger, Rod
    - Steiger, Rod, 1988 August 10; 115, B5047; 1.0 (Box 244)
    - Steiger, Rod, 1988 August 10; B5047; 1.0 (Box 245)
    - Steiger, Rod, Circa 1980s; B5047; 1.0 (Box 246)
  - Teller, Edward
    - Teller, Edward, 1985 May 20; 15; 1.0 (Box 247)
    - Teller, Edward, 1985 May 20; 16; 1.0 (Box 248)
    - Teller, Edward, 1988 January 26; 79, B5001; 1.0 (Box 249)
    - Teller, Edward, 1988 January 26; B5001; 1.0 (Box 250)
    - Teller, Edward, 1988 January 26; B5002; 1.0 (Box 251)
  - Tillich, Hannah, 1985 June 4; 21; 1.0 (Box 252)
  - Waldo, Hilde
    - Waldo, Hilde, 1988 January 27; B5009, B5010; 1.0 (Box 253)
    - Waldo, 1988 January 27; B5009; 1.0 (Box 254)
    - Waldo, 1988 January 27; B5010; 1.0 (Box 255)
  - Weiner, Lynn, 1988 March 24; B5038; 1.0 (Box 256)
  - Wilder, Billy, Circa 1980s; 78; 1.0 (Box 257)
  - Wolff, Helen
    - Wolff, Helen, 1985 June 15; 32; 1.0 (Box 258)
    - Wolff, Helen, 1985 June 15; 33; 1.0 (Box 259)
    - Wolff, Helen, 1985 June 15; 34; 1.0 (Box 260)
    - Wolff, Helen, 1988 March 4; 90, 5022, 5023; 1.0 (Box 261)
    - Wolff, Helen, 1988 March 4; 91, 5024, 5025; 1.0 (Box 262)
    - Wolff, Helen, 1988 March 4; B5022; 1.0 (Box 263)
    - Wolff, Helen, 1988 March 4; B5023; 1.0 (Box 264)
    - Wolff, Helen, 1988 March 4; B5024; 1.0 (Box 265)
    - Wolff, Helen part 1, 1988 March 4; 5022 through 5024; 1.0 (Box 266)
    - Wolff, Helen part 2 and Peter Selz part 1, 1988 March 4; 5025; 1.0 (Box 267)
    - Wolff, Helen, and Selz, Peter, 1988 March 4; B5025; 1.0 (Box 268)
    - Wolff, second VHS copy, Circa 1980s; 1.0 (Box 269)
  - Zimmer, Christiane
    - Zimmer, Christiane, 1985 May 13; 9; 1.0 (Box 270)
    - Zimmer, Christiane, 1985 May 13; 10; 1.0 (Box 271)
    - Zimmer, Christiane (Side A); Jonas, Hans (Side B), undated; 56; 1.0 (Box 272)
    - Zimmer, Christiane, 1988 January 21; 15A; 1.0 (Box 273)